This is the Taeyangho.
这, 是太阳号恩情列车
火车上的是曹县的太阳
On board is Kim Jong-un,
the ruler of North Korea.
金带将军✋😭✋
He almost never leaves his country.
他基本上不出国
But when he does, he travels on rail,
当他出国时
in the so-called moving fortress.
他会坐托马斯小火车
Right now, he just left Pyongyang.
现在, 他离开平壤
His destination is the Vostochny Cosmodrome in Russia to meet Vladimir Putin.
动身前往俄国的东方航天发射场会见普京
The journey will take him around two days and well over a thousand kilometers through foreign land
这趟行程约耗时两天, 将在别国领土上跨越千里
Kim has many enemies.
将军这一生树敌无数
How does the Taeyangho keep him safe?
星穹列车是如何护他平安的？
Only a few North Koreans have access to the regular internet.
光之国没几个家接入信息高速路
If you're able to watch this video,
要是bro能看到这个视频
you're probably living in a country that allows you to access all the websites and
那bro大概率生在长城外
platforms the world has to offer.
能在信息高速路上畅通无阻
Well, most of them.
🤔大概...无阻...吧？
NordVPN can help you bypass geo-blockings.
碰上封路了?🤔没关系!我们的神奇妙妙小魔法能帮您绕个路
Streaming sites such as Disney Plus often have drastically different catalogs depending on
在Nord上选择您从未踏足的精神故乡
where you're surfing from.
把锁区和差异化定价移交蔡司
Select a country and enjoy content that's usually not available in your area.
爽刷 *不可名状之平台*
Platforms like Booking.com often have different prices in different countries as well.
享受低价区的便宜青旅
Use a VPN to find the cheapest offer and save some money.
您不止可以用*不可名状黑魔法*做赛博土耳其人
Additionally, the built-in Darknet Monitor can notify you when your personal data is being leaked online
魔法部还会帮bro守好bro的赛博一亩三分地
Threat protection can block harmful advertising and trackers.
让您的赛博肥水不流外人田
Go to NordVPN.com slash Furn TV and get an extra four months on a two-year plan,
免受电报上野生CIA的红色代码骚扰
plus a 30-day money-back guarantee for your secure online journey.
现在点点屏幕下方小黄车
We appreciate NordVPN for sponsoring this episode.
魔法部还提供30天无理由
By checking them out,
给魔法部苞米
you support our reporting.
我们也能爽赤回扣😋
恩情列车有另两辆车全程护送
The Taeyangho is escorted by two additional trains.
一列在前开路
One drives ahead to check for dangers,
like planted explosives on the tracks or ambushes on the sides.
按v点亮越共, 或者当当人肉ERA
The other one secures the back.
另一列殿后
加装有重甲
It is filled with heavily armed security,
时刻准备化身铁路Strv122B+护卫将军
ready to rush to the Supreme Leader's rescue if need be.
A helicopter scouts the area ahead.
还有一架直升机
在朝鲜境内时刻护送专列
He accompanies the convoy the entire time Kim is traveling through North Korean territory.
以及运输机派遣人员在沿途机场驻守
Cargo planes station additional personnel at the closest airports along the route.
The Taeyangho has reinforced bulletproof windows.
专列装有防弹玻璃
车体外部也时刻准备跟后羿coser爆了
Its walls and bottom are hardened to withstand explosions.
Multiple compartments are carrying heavy weaponry
车上多个车厢载有重火力
The train is equipped to fight back against attacks from above with anti-aircraft missles
专列亦载有防空导弹、反坦克导弹与重机枪,
It also carries anti-tank missiles and two machine guns to aggressively fend off attacks
随时准备肘击意图射日者
from either side of the tracks.
护太阳系平安
If all defenses fail,
即便这些手段都失效了也毋需惊慌
the train carries a helicopter so Kim can flee from the scene.
车上还有一架直升机带将军穿云仪表飞行
All this makes Kim's train extremely safe,
这一切, 让太阳号安全无比
but also extremely heavy.
也让专列和太阳本人一样是投注
The Taeyangho travels at only 60 kilometers per hour,
你不懂大胃袋这一块让太阳号只能跑60迈
sometimes even slower,
考虑到曹县的优质的铁路维护
due to the poor condition of railways in North Korea.
有时还跑不到60
When the train passes by a station,
专列跨站时
the power is cut off on all other tracks.
其它轨道的电源会被切断
There are 20 railway stations in the country that were built solely for this one train.
光之国内, 亦有二十个车站是专为将军而建
受胃袋这一块的影响
Because of the slow speeds,
Kim might be on the road for several days on end,
将军可能得在车上待好几天
just like during this particular trip to meet Putin.
像他这次去见普大帝
On board, he has everything he needs to govern his country day and night.
车上备有他治理国家所需的一切必需品
An office with a desk,
带一间桌子的办公室
laptop, television, fax machine,
一台批判性使用的笔记本, 一架台灯, 与一台电视
satellite phone, and a map of China in the Korean peninsula on the wall.
还有一部卫星电话, 和一副朝鲜及中国地图
A reception room.
接待室
A meeting room with a table.
还有一间有桌子的会议室
The interior style is quite eclectic.
车厢的内饰风格挺"兼收并蓄"的
Most rooms are entirely white,
大多都刷成纯白色
with shiny wooden floors.
铺有实木地板
室内摆有律师和粉色的沙发
There are green and hot pink sofas,
ivory and turquoise curtains,
窗边挂的是象牙白与绿松石色的窗帘
flower-shaped lamps, and zebra-patterned fabric seats.
另有花朵形的挂壁灯及斑马纹椅子
But the highlight of the train is the restaurant.
不过真正牛逼的在于伙房
国际化这一块, 中日韩俄法, 一应俱全
On board, you can find all sorts of delicacies from Korean,
Russian, Chinese, Japanese,
and French cuisine.
Kim Jong-un won't get bored during the journey either.
将军也不会在旅途中感到无聊
The train has singers on board,
车上有一位歌手
who serenade the Supreme Leader personally.
专为他服务
When stepping off the train,
将军下车时,
two on-board armored Mercedes limousines are unloaded for the last mile.
列车上两辆防弹迈巴赫就会为其打通"最后一公里"
Train travel has a long tradition in the Kim family.
爱上火车是金家的传统
This is the Kumsusan Palace,
这是锦绣山太阳宫
where the remains of Kim Il-sung and Kim Jong-il are laid to rest.
即金日成与金正日遗体所在之处
Right next to their remains,
遗体旁,
摆放有其专列的1:1模型
you'll find life-size models of their personal train carriages.
There's even said to be a painting of Kim Jong-il proudly standing next to his train.
及金正日与其专列的合照
A map with small lights shows the many journeys they took.
一副带有灯光的地图展示着其生前足迹
Taking the train started as a safety precaution.
乘火车对他们来说是一种安全保护措施
据传金正日怕乘飞机
Kim Jong-il was reportedly also just a bit afraid of flying.
2001年, 他曾在去莫斯科的路上
In 2001, he took a train journey lasting almost a month,
all the way to Moscow,
跟火车呆了近一个月
covering a total of 20,000 kilometers.
刷了两万里程
一位叫康斯坦丁·普利科夫斯基的俄罗斯官员陪他走完了这一程
A Russian official named Konstantin Pulikovsky accompanied him.
After the journey, he published a book about his experiences.
事后, 他出了一本书来讲这段经历
Much to the irritation of both the Russian and North Korean governments.
让曹县和俄国当局都大为火光
That's because for a long time,
因为长期以来
the Korean leader's trains were shrouded in utter mystery.
曹县领导人专列的行程及其内饰
都深埋于世界未解之谜的深水区
It was never announced when they would move and where.
Also, the interior was largely kept secret.
此前也从未被公开
In 2004, Kim Jong-il's train passed through the Ryongchon Station near the border with China
主体93年, 金正日的专列经过中朝边境旁的龙川站
Just hours later, a massive explosion killed about 160 people and injured 1,300 more
仅仅一小时后, 该站就发生了一次爆炸, 致死约160人, 致伤1300多人
Supposedly, a train parked at the station laden with oils and chemicals was hitting power lines
据称, 一辆装满化学药品与燃油的列车, 在停站期间接触了坠落的电线
There were speculations that this might have been an assassination attempt.
有人猜测这是一次失败的暗杀
这种说法不无道理
That's not entirely unlikely.
There have been many reports of internal power struggles in North Korea over the decades.
有关朝鲜内部吉列权力豆蒸的报道真不少
The security of the train was reportedly boosted after the incident.
报道称, 爆炸事件让列车保卫也上了强度
In 2009, Russian photographers were banned from taking pictures of the train while it was
主体98年, 将军前往俄罗斯会见时任俄国总统德米特里·梅德韦杰夫时
en route to the then-President Dmitry Medvedev.
还顺手碎了几个俄罗斯摄影师的水表梦
Entire villages in Siberia were instructed to stay indoors until the train had passed.
在西伯利亚, 还有个村庄接旨, 称村民在专列驶过前不得出门
In the era of smartphones,
不过在如今, 智能手机时代
this is no longer possible and,
这么干多少有点理想主义
in some cases, not really desired.
且, 某些情况下, 将军也不想这么干
Because the train also serves propaganda purposes.
因为专列有宣传作用
The Taeyangho fittingly means sun.
태양호 意为太阳
其在朝鲜已然成为权力的象征
It has become a powerful symbol for North Korea.
Kim Jong-un is said to use it to appear down to earth and close to the people.
据传金正恩以此来展现平易近人的形象, 拉近与群众的距离
In stark contrast to the lofty image of the US president and his giant jumbo jet.
以与美国总统所乘的巨型喷气客机形成鲜明对比
And political leaders traveling by train is one way or another, a symbol.
且无论如何, 政治领袖乘火车出行都是一种象征
俄乌冲突开始后,
After the invasion of Ukraine,
the airspace above the country became unsafe.
乌克兰领空不再安全
许多西方领导人开始从波兰坐火车前往基辅
Many Western leaders started to visit Kiev by train through Poland.
This has been coined as iron diplomacy.
这被称为"钢铁外交"
在朝鲜这
In the case of North Korea,
太阳号恰恰凸显了这个国家的封闭
the Taeyangho in some ways accentuates just how uniquely isolated the country is.
The supreme leaders rarely,
其最高领袖极少,
or perhaps never, visit most parts of the world.
或者说完全没造访过这个世界上的大多数地方
There is also a certain irony in the train supposedly symbolizing the modesty of the Kim
据说这辆专列还象征着金氏家族的谦逊, 着实有些讽刺
Journeys always have a destination.
旅行总会有个目的地
现在我们的太阳号终于到达了它的目的地, 俄罗斯东方航天发射场
Kim's train finally arrives at Vostochny Cosmodrome
He is greeted with one of the longest and perhaps most uncomfortable handshakes in history
将军迎来了历史上最漫长、或许也是最令人难堪的握手之一
Then, Putin gives him the full tour.
而后, 普京带他考察了发射场
一处航天港, 一家飞机制造厂
A spaceport, an aircraft factory,
and the Pacific Fleet.
以及太平洋舰队
Later, there's vodka,
稍后, 是伏特加
a ballet performance,
芭蕾舞
and a walrus show.
与海象表演
The reason the two men meet is quite serious, however
不过, 二人会面的原因却不似刚刚的行程那般歌舞升平
Russia is running low on ammunition and allies in its war against Ukraine.
俄罗斯在这场战争中捉襟见肘, 众叛亲离
而朝鲜刚好有不少兵马弹药
North Korea has enormous stocks of ammo and is not afraid to supply it.
作为回报, 朝鲜能得到俄罗斯的技术支持
In return, the country could receive technical support from Russia for building new
satellites and missiles for its nuclear weapons program.
以建设其卫星与核导弹工程
No official outcome has been announced,
对此双方并未做出官方声明
but Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov recently visited Pyongyang shortly after the meeting
但俄罗斯外交部长拉夫罗夫在会面后访问了平壤
He thanked North Korea for its support in the Ukraine conflict and reaffirmed the
他感谢了朝鲜在俄乌冲突中对俄罗斯的支持
并重申了二国间的伙伴关系
partnership between both countries.
作为回报,
North Korea, in turn,
officially recognized the territories captured by Russia as Russian sovereign territory.
朝鲜方面承认为俄罗斯所占有的乌克兰领土归俄罗斯所有
Lavrov didn't commit on weapons deliveries,
拉夫罗夫并未承认朝鲜在对俄供应武器
but according to the U.S. government, North Korea has already delivered over 1,000
但根据美国政府的说法
containers of ammunition and military equipment to Russia.
朝鲜已经向俄罗斯提供了超过1000箱弹药及军需品
国际上, 朝鲜及俄罗斯都没剩多少盟友
North Korea and Russia both have very few international allies left.
当太阳号成为朝鲜的国家象征时,
While the Taeyangho tries to be a symbol of power for North Korea,
it is also a sign of the country's deep isolation.
它却也体现着朝鲜的孤立无援
Vladimir Putin has accepted an offer to visit Kim Jong-un in return.
普京不久前接受了金正恩的访朝邀请
This would be a good chance for him to take his very own ghost train.
对他, 这或许是个乘上他自己的"鬼魂"专列的好机会
声明: 原作者观点不代表译者立场, 中字采用 CC BY-SA 4.0 进行授权